Keith Rich
Homework 3
CSC 520
On our honor, as SFSU students, we Keith, Jack, did not give or receive inappropriate
help with this assignment. All group members participated in this work, and all agree with the submission.

Part 1: Use the CF pumping theorem, and the fact that the CFLs are closed under intersection with a
regular language, to show that L ∉ CFLs.

--if D or V or C is a CFL then so is ∑ (if Q then P)

--if ∑ is NOT a CFL then neither is D or V or C (if not P then not Q)

Then w ∈ L∪ and |w| >= k. therefore the pumping theorem guarantees apply.

L∩ = L∩ 0^k a^(k+1) d^(k+2)

|xyz|<= k	vy ∉ eps

w = uvxyz	w^2 = uv^2 xy^2 z

Break into regions
0^k	a^(k+1)		d^(k+2)
1	2		3

(1,1): uv^2 xy^2 all fall into 0's region and z is everything else. By pumping in region (1,1) we end up with a large surplus of 0's. More then our L is allowing to permit.
(2,2): v^2 xy^2 all fall into a's region, u is in region 1, z is everything else. By pumping in region (2,2) we end up with a large surplus of a's. More then our L is allowing to permit.
(3,3): v^2 xy^2z all fall into d's region and u is everything else. By pumping in region (3,3) we end up with a large surplus of d's. More then our L is allowing to permit.
(1,2): uv^2 is in region 1, xy^2 is in region 2, and z is in region 3. By pumping in we end up with few d's and many 0's and a's. therefore this is no longer in our L
(1,3): beacuse we specified |xyz|<= k the proof holds up.
(2,3): v^2 is in region 2, xy^2 z is in region 3, and u is in region 1. By pumping in we end up having more then one more k in a and two more k's d then we have o's all together 


Part 2: Write a characteristic function for the language accepted by the TM
represented in the macro language diagram.

L = { w : ((a*b*)*b, |a|=|b|+2(k+1) ∪ ((a*b*)*a, |b|=|a|+2k+1 ∪ ((a*b*)*a, |a|=|b|+2k+1 ∪ ((a*b*)*b, |a|=|b|+2(k+1) , k>=0}
---------------------------------------------------
read a, read b cycle
read a, read ?, read a, read a, cycle
read a, read ?, read a, read ?, hit y
read a, read ?, read a, read ?, read ?, hit n
read a, read ?, read ?, hit y
read a, read ?, read ?, read ? , hit n

read ?,
a--b
   ?--a--a--?--y
             --n
      a--?--y
            ?--n
?--b--b
   b--?--y
         ?--n
   ?--y
      ?--n